# Paul A. Horton

Arizona State University - Software Engineering B.S. and Applied Physics B.S.

School Address Home Address Phone: (520) 869-1275
6356 S Sagewood 7443 W Palm Brook Pl Email: pahorton@asu.edu
Mesa, AZ 85212 Tucson, AZ 85743 Website: hortonpaul.com

# Summary

Paul Horton is a Barrett Honors student pursuing dual undergraduate degrees in Software Engineering and Applied Physics at Arizona State University. He is also pursuing a masters degree in Software Engineering through a 4+1. With his degrees he intends enter a doctorate program in Computational Physics and conduct research in the fields of Astrophysics and Quantum Computing.

# Education

M.S., B.S. Software Engineering, Arizona State University - Polytechnic Campus, Mesa, AZ

Ira A. Fulton Schools of Engineering

Anticipated Graduation: May 2018 (B.S), May 2019 (M.S)

Major GPA: 4.06 Dean's List: Every Semester

B.S. Applied Physics, Arizona State University - Polytechnic Campus, Mesa, AZ

College of Integrative Sciences and Arts Anticipated Graduation: May 2018

Major GPA: 4.01 Dean's List: Every Semester

Honors College, Arizona State University - Polytechnic Campus, Mesa, AZ Barrett, the Honors College

# Highlights click for more info

- Developing a quantum key generator to study quantum cryptography for an honors thesis.
- Researching teams in short-form programming competitions to improve engineering education.
- Leading software development for a solar powered educational library to help South Pacific schools.
- Coordinating the logistics of a large-scale collegiate programming competition at ASU.

# Skills in order of proficiency

### Programming Languages

- Python
- Java
- C++
- LATEX
- C
- JavaScript
- Assembly
- node.js
- Verilog
- Prolog
- HTML/CSS

#### Software

- Adobe CC
- Microsoft Office
- Eclipse
- MATLAB
- Amazon Web Services
- Unity
- Xilinx ISE

## Relevant Coursework

#### **Physics**

- Vector Mechanics
- Statistics
- Quantum Mechanics
- Mathematical Methods

#### Software

- Software Systems
- Embedded Systems
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Systems Design

Paul A. Horton

# **Experiences**

#### Work

Self-Employed Tutoring, Mesa, AZ Private Physics Tutor October 2016 - Present

Maker Research Group, ASU

January 2016 - Present

Research Assistant and Data Collector

• Undertaking in qualatative data collection of makers at maker faires through surveys and interviews in order to better understand how makers relate to engineering education.

Barrett, the Honors College, ASU

August 2015 - December 2016

Teaching Assistant and Writing Tutor for Freshman Honors Reading Course

Ethical Responsibility Among Undergraduate Engineering Students, Purdue August 2015 - May 2016 Research Assistant and Data Collector

• Collaborated with Purdue at ASU to research engineering students and their view of ethics and their ethical considerations.

STEAM (Science Technology Engineering Art Math) Labs, ASU

August 2014 - May 2016

K-12 Engineering Education Outreacher and Tinkerer

• Worked with interdisciplinary engineering undergraduates to teach K12 students the engineering design process through creative chain-reaction machines.

# Extracurricular Projects

Astronomical Instrumentation Lab, ASU

January 2017 - Present

Research Assistant and FPGA Programmer

- Programming ROACH board's firmware to study the formation of stars and it's relation to magnetic fields.
- Continuing the work of a previous student to increase the resolution of instruments for astronomical optical interferometry.

Fulton Undergraduate Research Initiate, ASU Mentor Guided Researcher August 2016 - Present

• Analyzing the effectiveness of teams in short-form programming competitions and how their collaboration methods can bring value to the classroom setting.

Desert Hacks, ASU

June 2016 - Present

Student Organizer

• Organize a large scale 24 hour programming competition by helping coordinate the logistics and sponsorship of the event.

### Extracurricular Groups and Scholarships

Barrett Polytechnic Writing Colloquium

August 2015 - Present

Computer Science Club at ASU Polytechnic

January 2015 - Present

Broadening the Reach of Engineering Through Computer Science Scholar

August 2014 - Present

Paul A. Horton

### Coursework Projects

All course projets were accomplished at Arizona State University unless otherwise noted.

Projects noted with a \* indicate that the project was conducted in parallel with the class in order to earn Honors credit.

SolarSPELL (Solar Powered Educational Learning Library)

Fall 2016 - Present

• Redesigning the front and back end of a portable offline database of documents and videos useful for educators of developing nations in the South Pacific.

Fourier Series Programs in Python

Spring 2016

Graphing Mechanical Systems using MATLAB\*

Fall 2015

Simulation of Parking Structure and Streets in Shibuya using Unity, ASU and Waseda Summer 2015

• Explored urban areas of Tokyo for the purpose of visualization and simulation of population and vehicular traffic.

Educational Math Adventure Game in Java\*

Spring 2015

Phoenix Zoo Audio Exhibit Remodel using Raspberry Pi\*

Fall 2014 - Spring 2015

Mathematical Analysis of Massé Shots in Billiards\*

Fall 2014

## Personal Projects

### **Independent Projects**

IBM Quantum Experience

January 2017 - Present

• Independently teaching self quantum computing using IBM's public quantum computer.

# **Hackathon Projects**

SDHacks, University of California San Diego

August 2016

• Developed an Amazon Echo skill that acts as a recipe assistant using Node.js.

SBHacks, University of California Santa Barbara

April 2016

• Used IBM's Bluemix and Node-RED to create a smart weight sensor that gave updates on household items.

Beach Hacks, California State University Long Beach

April 2016

Created a numerical solving app with image recognition using OpenCV.

HackArizona, University of Arizona

January 2016

• Created a VR Engineering Education and teambuilding app using Google Cardboard.

Last updated: September 10, 2017 hortonpaul.com